Bruce Bellingham Papers
© 2011 University of Connecticut
Bruce Bellingham Papers.
undated, 1945-2003.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Bellingham, Bruce.
9.1 linear feet.
The collection contains notes, class materials, photocopies, transparencies, research, scores, correspondence and publications pertaining to Professor Bellingham's scholarly research in the history of music.
MSS20100055
Biography
Bruce Bellingham joined the faculty of the Eastman School of Music in 1968, and came to the University of Connecticut as a professor of music history in the School of Fine Arts in 1974. In addition to teaching in the Music Department, Bellingham also gave pre-concert talks at the Jorgensen Center for the Performing Arts at UConn, taught at the Center for Learning in Retirement and the Adult Learning Program in West Hartford. He retired in 2003.
An active member of the New Britain Symphony, the Amphibian Jazz Ensemble, and the Viola de Gamba Society, Bellingham was chairman of the Hop River Chamber Music series. He was also a long-time patron of the Jorgensen Center for the Performing Arts and a founding member of its volunteer organization, Co-Stars, he extended his support through many programs, especially the Jorgensen Outreach for Youth (JOY!). With his wife, Deborah Walsh Bellingham, he received the Outstanding Volunteer Award in 2009.
Bruce Bellingham, professor emeritus of music, died suddenly of a heart attack on January 3, 2010, at the age of 71.
Scope and Content
The collection contains notes, photocopies, transparencies, research, scores, correspondence and publications pertaining to Professor Bellingham's scholarly research in the history of music.
Arrangement
Series I: Inventory ( undated, 1945-2003 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Bellingham, Bruce.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Notebooks.; Publications.; Photocopies.; Notes.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials were donated in 2010 by Deborah Walsh Bellingham.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Inventory, undated, 1945-2003
  - (Box 1)
    - Beethoven 5th, Bellingham's notes on Beethoven, undated
    - 194 Class materials, revised, 1980 Spring
    - 194 Class materials, 1984 Spring
    - 193 Class materials, Master, undated
    - 20th century, Stravinsky materials, undated, 1970-1983
    - Medieval motet, Paintings, Cathedral handouts, undated
    - Dufay: Supremum est mortalibus, undated
    - Dufay: Motet "Nuper Rosarum flores,", undated
    - Iconography lecture script (long), 1971, 1973
    - Viol Consort, 1980
    - Ruth Markowitz thesis, 1961
    - Monteverdi "Dixit Dominus" from Vespers, undated; [2 folders]
    - Gabrieli, undated
    - Symphony, undated, 1999
    - Symphonic Poem 413, 1982 Spring
    - D. Cooke, Wagner's Ring-Transparencies, undated
    - 193 Baroque, 1st outline, undated
    - 193 Medieval/Renaissance lecture notes, undated
    - Syntagma musicum transparencies, 1991, 1997
    - Reviews and articles (photocopies), undated, 1945-1970
    - Beethoven, Violin Concerto, undated, 1958-1962
  - (Box 2)
    - String Literature, 1970 Spring
    - Chamber Music 215 materials and master copy, Classical on, 1978 Spring
    - Research notes, bibliography (card files), undated
  - (Box 3)
    - Research notes, bibliography (card files), undated
  - (Box 4)
    - Storrs Collegium Musicum, undated
    - Josquin des Prez, Ave Maria, Rhetoric, transparencies and notes, undated, 1993
    - Italian Ricarari/Conzoni Bibliography, undated
    - Josquin Festival, 1971
    - Amati Gaspar da Salo, notes, transparencies, undated
    - Correspondence (recital attendance), 2002-2003
    - Notes, transparencies, maps, undated, 1997, 2001
      - 287 Music History 1600-1700
      - 413 Fantasia and Instrumental music, Italy/England 1590-1646
      - 287 Music History, Greece - 1600
      - 413 Renaissance Seminar to Monteverdi, 1997 Spring
      - 20th Century, general
  - (Box 5)
    - Notes, transparencies, maps, undated, 2001
      - Symphony Analyses, 18th century, 19th century Italian, undated
      - 411 Mahler, 2001 Spring
    - Viola de Gamba Society materials, 1982-1984, 1989
  - (Box 6-7)
    - Notes, transparencies, research, scores and correspondence pertaining to his research on Alfonso Ferrabosco, 1959-1980s